<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Top 10 SQL Injection</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As in my article on Command Injection the aim of this post is to consolidate my knowledge on an issue in the OWASP Top 10 and add to it as I learn more so I have a constantly expanding reference guide and hopefully help out anyone who stumbles across this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-SQL-Injection</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-SQL-Injection</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>SSRF - Location and Exploitation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Server Side Request Forgery (SSRF) is an exploit that allows an attacker to make arbitrary HTTP requests from the web server. These could be to access an internal network or to reach out to a malicious site, essentially turning the web server into a proxy server.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/SSRF</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/SSRF</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Top 10 XXE (or taking liberties with acronyms)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As in my article on Command Injection the aim of this post is to consolidate my knowledge on an issue in the OWASP Top 10 and add to it as I learn more so I have a constantly expanding reference guide and hopefully help out anyone who stumbles across this.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-XXE</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-XXE</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hacking WebDAV with Granny and Grandpa</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Web Distributed Authoring and Versioning (WebDAV) is an extension on HTTP that provides further methods to allow users to control content more readily. Webdav allows authorised users to create, move and alter files on a server. They are used by software that supports publishing of data such as sharepoint and outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Webdav-with-Granny-and-Grandpa</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Webdav-with-Granny-and-Grandpa</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Finding, Exploiting and Escalating LFI</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Local File Inclusion or LFI is a vulnerability in web applications where input can be manipulated to read other files on the system that were not intented to be read by the web server. It occurs when the application accesses a file on the system using input that can be altered by the user. Then it is just a case of finding the right level of back tracks (../) to locate the files of interest.
LFI is a useful vulnerability to find but if there are no interesting files on the server there isn’t much you can do with it. Or is there?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/LFI-to-RCE</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/LFI-to-RCE</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ghostcat Vulnerability (CVE-2020-1938)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;To continue my theme of better late than never I have a quick write up of the ghost cat vulnerability. Probably old news to most but wanted to get my learning down on “paper” to help me organise my thoughts. I will start with a few definitions and then move on to the POC and remediations. The POC is from the room on Tryhackme.com.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/Ghostcat-Vulnerability</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Ghostcat-Vulnerability</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Top 10 OS Command Injection</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to dig a little deeper into the OWASP top 10. I find web security such a vast subject (with new issues being found daily) that instead of chasing around every new issue I come across my time would be better spent getting a better understanding of the OWASP Top 10 first. I have had the chance to set up labs or practice them on hack the box but this will be the first time I consolidate my knowledge in a blog for future reference. I believe this understanding will help me when I explore more niche vulnerabilities in the future. For those new to the subject and not aware of these 10, I list them below. Further details can also be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-Command-Injection</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/OWASP-Top-10-Command-Injection</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
